All right, we're going to do two
problems in this video. The first one
tells us it wants us to receive an input
for a number, then multiply that number
by two, then add nine, then subtract
three, then divide by two, then subtract
the original number, and then print the
results. All right, so let's get
started. Uh, the first thing we're going
to want to do is we're going to want to
put our name as a comment at the top. So
name,
and then we're going to want to put a
brief description of what our program
does. um
does some cool math.
Um if this was a real world project,
you'd want probably want to be more
descriptive. In this case, we're just
doing math. All right. So, let's take an
input for a number. Let's start with
that. So, right here, we're going to say
um let my number equal prompt
Please enter a number.
Um, this prompt remember always returns
a string. So if we want it to be an
actual number so that we can do the
multiplication, the addition and the
subtraction, then we need to convert it.
Um, so I if they enter a number with
decimal places, I want to keep track of
that. So I'm going to use parse float.
So I'm going to turn my string into a
floating number. So we'll say parse
float and that's takes in an input of a
string and turns it into a float. So I'm
going to prompt them for a number. Going
to get a number going to as a string.
I'm going to convert it into a number
and I'm going to store it.
Once I've done that, um I know I'm going
to need that original number later. So
before I do multiplication, I need to
make sure that I don't change what this
number is. So, I should probably create
a new variable. So, I'm going to say let
um running number equal and we said
multiply that number by two. So, we'll
say my num times two.
And then it says add nine. All right.
So, we can just access our running
number again and say running number
equals itself plus 9. So now we've added
9. So let's say we took three. 3 * 2 is
6. 6 + 9 is 15. Um so then it says
subtract 3.
Running number
equals running number minus 3.
And then it wants us to divide by two.
So we'll say running number equals
running number divided by two.
And then it wants us to subtract the
original number. So we're going to say
running number equals running number
minus the original number is my number
because we haven't changed this
variable. We've just been changing
running number this whole time.
And then we need to print the result. So
I'm going to say alert
running number. So that should be our
final answer. So, if we save this and we
come over
to our browser and we um reload our
page, it'll say please enter a number.
If we enter three and we hit okay, the
result is three.
And I just realized I'm sharing the
wrong screen.
Okay, so I will reload this page and it
says please enter a number. I'm going to
enter three. If I hit enter, it runs all
those calculations and I get three. If I
reload the page and I enter 10, it runs
all those calculations and I get three.
The reason this is called magic math is
because no matter what number you enter
here, you will always get a three. So
you know you've written this correctly
if every time you run your program, you
get a three. So let's move on to problem
number two. Problem number two says to
rewrite the last problem using compound
assignment.
So um I'm going to start by grabbing my
number again but because I'm in the same
file I cannot reuse the same name. So
I'm going to call my variable instead of
calling it my number I'll call it uh num
two. So this is my second number that
I'm getting
and I'm getting information and I'm
turning it into a float. We can't do
anything with num two. We can't use
compound assignment on number two
because we need it to stay the same um
because we need to use it twice in our
program. However, all of these times
where we did running number equals
running number plus or minus, we can
change those to be compound assignment.
So let's do that. We'll say let running
number two equal
minum
* 2. That line has to stay the same. The
next line, however, can be shortened.
Instead of saying running number equals
running number + 9, we can say running
number plus= 9. The next line says
running number equals running number
minus 3. So we'll say running number
minus equals 3. The next line is wait,
let me just double check I've got all my
lines. 2 93. Okay, so next one is
divided by two. So we can say running
number divide equal 2.
And then we can do the last one, which
is running number um equals running
number minus my number. So we'll say
running number minus equals num two. And
I realized these are all supposed to be
running number two. If you're ever
trying to fix multiple lines at once, on
a Windows you'll hold the Alt key. On a
Mac, you'll hold the option key and you
can click into multiple places on your
computer and it allows you to type once
and have it be typed into all of those
places. So in all these places, I can
just type the number two and I've now
fixed those so they all say running
number two. So I get my number two
prompt. I take it and multiply it by two
and store it back. And then I'm
constantly using compound assignment to
add 9, subtract three, divide by two,
and then subtract whatever our original
number was. And once we're done,
we'll alert
our running number two. And we'll save
our code. So if everything works
perfectly, we should be able to enter um
any number on the first one and get
three and any number on the second one
and get three as well.
So, if we come back over, I'm going to
hit cancel
and cancel and reload the page. Okay,
please enter a number 10. Three. We knew
the first one worked, so that's not
surprising. Second one, we'll enter 10.
And we get three, which means we
successfully were able to adapt our
original um our original code to be use
to use compound assignment instead. And
that concludes this video. Thanks for
watching.